So here's our application
te bizim uygulama ve
and generally, it works fine.
genel olarak, iyi alyor.
Now there is a tiny issue when we place a new order,
imdi yeni bir sipari verdiimizde
if you inspect your order reducer file, you will see that on purchaseBurgerStart which of course
ufak bir sorun var, eer sipari redktrnz incelerseniz, sipari zerine tkladktan
is dispatched when we click on order,
sonra hangi siparii gnderdiimizi satn
when we send the order to the server,
aldnz greceksiniz.BurgerStart, siparii sunucuya
we set loading to false.
gnderdiimizde, ykleme ayarladmz yanl
Now that doesn't make any sense at all because here we want to set loading to true and we had it set
imdi bu hi bir anlam ifade etmiyor nk burada doruya yklemeyi yapmak istiyoruz ve bu derste
to true earlier in this course,
daha nce doru olarak
I messed this up when refactoring the reducer.
ayarlamtk, redktr yeniden monte ederken bunu kartrdm.
So this should of course be true, we want to show a spinner if we implement this functionality in our
Elbette bu doru olmal, eer bu ilevsellii bir sunucuya gnderdiimiz zaman
component when we are sending this to a server,
bu ilevsellii uygularsak bir spiker gstermek istiyoruz,
so this is the first tiny improvement.
bu yzden bu ilk kk gelime.
Now there's another improvement,
imdi baka bir gelime
if we are talking about placing an order, let's build a burger there.
var, eer sipari vermekten bahsediyorsak, orada bir burger hazrlayalm.
Now let's login first, submit this and we are redirected here back to our front page.
imdi nce giri yapalm, gnderin ve n sayfaya geri ynlendirildik.
Now that shouldn't happen, we fix this in the authentication section that we should be redirected to
imdi bu olmamal, biz dorulama blmne ynlendirmemiz gereken kimlik dorulama blmnde bunu
checkout
dzeltiriz
and we were there for a fraction of a second but somehow it decided to redirect us back to the front
ve bir saniyeliine bunun bir paras olduk ama bir ekilde bizi n sayfaya ynlendirmeye
page.
karar verdik.
So here we did correctly adjust set auth redirect but still it decided that a good place for us would
Bu yzden set auth ynlendirmesini doru bir ekilde ayarladk ama yine de bizim iin iyi bir yer olduuna karar
be the front page,
verdi, bu yzden dzeltmek
so it is something else I want to fix. Now
istediim baka bir ey. imdi bu
the reason for this problem with this wrong redirection is that we do redirect in the auth container here
yanl ynlendirme ile bu sorunun nedeni, biz bu kodu burada auth konteynerde ynlendirme
this code, there we set or we use our redirect path to redirect the user.
yapmak, ya da biz kullanc ynlendirmek iin ynlendirme yolumuzu kullanrz.
The problem is this happens in the auth container and in our app container, in our root app component
Sorun u ki, kimlik dorulama konteynrlar iin farkl yollar oluturduumuz kk uygulama
where we render different routes for different authentication statuses, there where we are authenticated,
bileenimizde, kimlik dorulama kapsaycsnda ve uygulama kabmzda, kimlik dorulamas yaptmz yerde,
we don't render the auth component anymore.
artk yetkilendirme bileenini oluturmuyoruz.
Hence the code in the auth component which would redirect us correctly to the checkout page will never
Bu nedenle, bizi deme sayfasna doru ekilde ynlendirecek olan auth bileenindeki kod
be used.
asla kullanlmayacaktr.
So to fix this, we can reintroduce the auth route into our set of routes in the authentication state,
Bunu dzeltmek iin, kimlik dorulama durumundaki rota kmemize auth rotasn yeniden ekleyebiliriz, u anda dezavantaj u anda dorulanm
now of course the disadvantage is that now authenticated users can visit the auth page, on the other hand, they
kullanclarn u anda auth sayfasn ziyaret edebilmeleri, dier taraftan, orada herhangi bir
can't do any harm there.
zarara neden olamazlar. .
You might of course also be able to find other solutions to redirect anywhere else
Elbette baka bir yere ynlendirmek iin baka zmler de bulabilirsin, ancak
but this is a quick and easy and safe solution to get back to the original behavior.
bu, orijinal davrana geri dnmek iin hzl ve kolay ve gvenli bir zm.
Now another issue we face is if I build a burger and I am logged in here, in that burger builder here,
imdi karlatmz bir baka konu da burger yapsam ve buraya giri yaptm zaman,
you will see that on certain screen sizes, the burger is positioned incorrectly it's not centered.
burger reticisi burada, baz ekran boyutlarnda burgerin yanl konumlandrldn greceksiniz.
The reason for this is that the burger has a width which is adjusted to the viewport but it's always
Bunun nedeni, burgerin grnm alanna gre ayarlanan bir genilie
inside a div which takes 100% of the width of its wrapping element
sahip olmas, ancak her zaman sarma elemannn geniliinin%
and that would be this div
100'n alan bir
which also dictates a a certain width, 80% in this case, the checkoutSummary.
div ierisindedir ve bu da,% 80 Bu durumda, checkoutSummary.
So the checkoutSummary here is dictating a certain width for our burger and that is influencing how
Buradaki checkoutSummary, burgerimiz iin belirli bir genilii dikte ediyor ve bu da iyi burgerimizin
our well burger is displayed here.
burada nasl grntlendiini etkiliyor.
To fix that, we can go to our components, to the checkoutSummary we can find it under order, checkout
Bunu dzeltmek iin, siparilerimize, deme zetine bulabildiimiz checkoutSummary'a ve daha
summary and there where we set the width to 500px for wider displays.
geni ekranlar iin genilii 500px'e ayarlayabildiimiz kasaya, bileenlerimize gidebiliriz.
In the end I don't want to do that,
Sonunda bunu yapmak istemiyorum,
I want to stick to the 80% I have by default and now with that, if we go back to the application
varsaylan olarak sahip olduum% 80 oranna sahip olmak istiyorum ve imdi bununla birlikte, eer uygulamaya geri
and we build a new burger I am logged in here already,
dnersek ve yeni bir burger hazrlarz, imdiden buraya
this burger should now be nicely centered on all device screens, so this is looking much better now,
giri yaptm. burger imdi tm cihaz ekranlarnda gzelce ortalanmal, bu yzden imdi daha iyi grnyor,
so now the burger is looking good all the time, no matter where we we're viewing it.
bu yzden imdi nerede izlediimiz nemli deil, burger her zaman iyi grnyor.
Now there's one other visual glitch I want to get rid of and that is on small devices,
Artk kurtulmak istediim baka bir grsel aksama var ve kk cihazlarda, eer
if we open our side nav and I click on a link, it navigates there correctly without errors but
yan navuzu aarsak ve bir linke tklarsam, hata olmadan doruca oraya gider, fakat yan
it doesn't close
navay kapatmaz.
the side nav, I have to manually do that.
bunu elle yapmak iin.
Of course it should close the side nav whenever we click a link here.
Tabii ki burada bir balanty tkladmzda yandaki nav'u kapatmal.
Now to fix this we have to go into our sideDrawer where we in the end have our sideDrawer here and
imdi bunu dzeltmek iin yan tarafmza girmemiz gerekiyor. Buralarda yan tarafmza gidiyoruz ve
there we have the navigation items
orada gezinme elerine sahibiz
and now we want to ensure that whenever we click a navigation item, we essentially close that drawer.
ve imdi bir navigasyon esini tklattmzda, aslnda ekmeceyi kapattmzdan emin olmak istiyoruz.
So we essentially want to emit or execute this closed method, the method we get on the closed prop in
Bu nedenle, bu kapal yntemde, bu sideDrawer bileeninde kapal prop'a aldmz yntemi
this sideDrawer component.
gerekten yaymak veya uygulamak istiyoruz.
Now to do that, we could for example simply listen to a click anywhere on the sideDrawer, now that of course
imdi bunu yapmak iin, rnein, sadece sideDrawer'n herhangi bir yerinde bir tklamay dinleyebiliriz, imdi elbette ki
would mean that not only clicking on links would close it. We could also go into the navigation items
sadece balantlarn tklanmas onu kapatmak anlamna gelmez. Gezinme elerine de gidebilir ve
and try to register onClick listener there too, I'll go with the general closing strategy here.
onClick dinleyicisine de kayt yaptrmay deneyebiliriz, burada genel kapan stratejisiyle gideceim.
So on a click on the sideDrawer in general, let's try to then reach out to props.closed which should
Bu yzden genel olarak sideDrawer'a bir tklama ile daha sonra sahne alanlarna ulamaya alalm. kapal bu bileenin ana bileeninde ele
be handled in the parent component of this component and close this side menu.
alnmal ve bu yan meny kapatn.
With that change in place, let's open the sideDrawer, if I click anywhere on it, it closes but that should
Bu deiiklikle birlikte, sideDrawer' aalm, eer zerinde herhangi bir yere tklarsam, kapanr, ama
be all right, if I click on
bu doru olmal,
orders, it therefore also closes.
eer siparileri tklarsam, bu da kapanr.
So now we got a sideDrawer which does work as we would expect it to work closing when we do navigate
imdi, etrafta gezinirken kapan almasn bekleyeceimiz gibi alan bir sideDrawer
around.
var.
These were a couple of visual glitches we had and fixes to them so that now our application looks and behaves
Bunlar, bizim uygulamamzn grne gre daha gzel ve daha fazlasn beklediimizden daha iyi ve daha iyi
nicer and more as we would expect it.
grnmesi iin, bizde birtakm grsel hatalar vard.